<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>a ऋ experiment</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/posts/ri-experiment/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/posts/ri-experiment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ऋ is a semivowel in Sanskrit that has taken various forms as it evolved to modern Indic languages, but since spelling is stubborn, we still use its equivalent in text. It&amp;rsquo;s read, however, like /ɾi/ in &lt;em&gt;Hindi-Urdu&lt;/em&gt; and /ɾu/ in &lt;em&gt;Marathi&lt;/em&gt;. In this experiment I try to gauge first language influence on the production and perception of /r/ as a(n) nucleus/onset-nucleus. /i/ and /u/ as vowels differ in their roundedness, and whether or not one says /r/ with their lips rounded influences what the Indic ṛ has evolved into in speech. In essence, the degree to which speakers of a tongue labialize their /r/ in various contexts dictates this.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>how much does first langauge matter when perceiving (and reacting to) other languages?</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/posts/first-lang/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/posts/first-lang/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you asked me that in fourth grade, I would&amp;rsquo;ve said yes. My reasoning would have been simple: you often translate your thoughts into a certain language, after thinking your thoughts in your first language (first language here is whatever language your mind performs cognitive tasks in, apart from visuals - but usually those abstract visuals are also a product of your environment and the language you think in so it gets circular). This happens without your knowledge if you&amp;rsquo;re relatively used to speaking that language (usually in multilingual communities). If you&amp;rsquo;re new to this, you might want to think of how you would approach writing something in a language you&amp;rsquo;re just learning. You explicitly say something in the language you&amp;rsquo;re accustomed to thinking in, in your head, as you write down or say whatever you have to in this other, new language.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
